sore muscles are the arch nemesis of any
level weight lifter and there really
might not be anything more Dreadful than
hopping out of bed in the morning after
a killer leg workout and hardly being
able to walk percussive massage guns may
be the answer you're looking for when it
comes to working out that soreness but
there's a lot for you to choose from
I've been using the theragon prime for a
couple weeks now and I have a lot to
share with you guys
what's up my people it's Jake back again
in the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time I
have the theragun Prime in this review
I'm going to take you through everything
that you need to know about this massage
going from the price and the features as
well as some pros and cons and of course
who should or maybe should not buy this
massage gun but before I really get
started on that I have to let you know
we've reviewed a good amount of massage
guns on barbin.com and if you want to
browse our best list just go and search
bar Bend best massage guns you can find
out for yourself which ones we like the
best
foreign
start talking about what I like about
the theragun prime if you aren't already
familiar with what a percussive massage
is it's essentially a combination of
rapid and repetitive pressure mixed in
with vibrational therapy so the head of
the massage gun is going to move rapidly
and it's going to apply enough pressure
mixed in with those vibrations to really
loosen up any stiffness that you might
have in your soft tissue okay so I want
to kick off what I like about the
theragun Prime with the handle so it
looks a little funky at first it's an
ergonomically designed handle I didn't
think I was gonna like it at first
because it does look a little funky like
I said but as I started using it I
actually grew to really enjoy it you
have different grips you can do that way
you can hit different body parts and
plus you can use two hands on it and use
it on somebody's back you know if you
want to the attachments are also really
nice you have four of them as you can
see right here in front of me but I
really like the material they're made of
they're not made of a hard classic which
is what you'll often find with the
massage gun like this those can be less
versatile I guess you could say because
you don't really want to use those hard
plastic attachments on any sensitive
areas such as your hands you know you
got a lot of Bones right here I don't
think that's a problem with any of these
really I mean they feel a little spongy
I guess you could say and they're not
gonna hurt you so that's really nice you
have five different speeds you can use
that way you know you can up the
intensity for any super stubborn areas
that you might be dealing with and I
really enjoy the therabody app it's a
super useful tool in my opinion because
it's going to show you exactly how to
use this massage gun trust me there's
more to it than simply placing it on an
injured muscle and just that'd be it
there's a specific way to go about it
and it's going to show you exactly how
to do so plus once you pair the theragon
prime to your phone via Bluetooth you
can control the intensity of this
massage gun through the app which is
pretty cool as you're setting up your
profile it's going to ask you what
activities you participate it in once
you do so that's when it's going to
really provide those routines based off
what you selected plus there's even a
section for any ailments that you might
be dealing with
[Music]
okay so let's talk about a few issues
you might run into with the theragun
prime let's talk about the speed
settings first I mentioned there's five
of them and that you can really increase
that intensity when necessary that's
great but I personally would like to see
a slower speed setting just for those
times where you're super sore and you
don't want a whole lot of pressure you
know on a sore muscle if you want to get
some extra blood flow in that area so
that'd be a nice little touch I really
like the attachments they're awesome I
just wish there was a fork attachment
thrown in with the original purchase
those are really versatile in my opinion
you can use them on your forearms your
biceps your calves your Achilles and
also think you can use them on either
side of your spine so that'd be a nice
little touch as well it's also kind of
loud
so if you plan on using this massage gun
while you're watching your favorite TV
show might want to crank up the volume
just a little bit and it's kind of
expensive this is listed right around
300 and that might be a turn off for
some people because you can absolutely
find some out there that are available
for a fraction of this price
foreign
so let's talk about price in a little
more detail now the theragon prime is
going to run you right around 300 now
shipping is free which is nice but let's
be honest that's a pretty penny for a
massage gun if you purchase this massage
gun directly through the therabody
website you do have the option of
financing your purchase through a firm
now you're gonna have to do a soft
credit check but once you do that we
have the option of making payments of 75
every two weeks or you can choose from
doing 50 a month or twenty five dollars
a month until you pay this off it's also
available on some other websites we
bought ours through Rogue and on top of
a firm they also allow you to use pay
later from PayPal if you decide to go
down that route you'll have the option
of making eighty dollar payments every
three months or 12 payments of thirty
dollars now three hundred dollars is not
cheap by any means necessary but you
know you compare the theragon prime to
going to see a massage therapist even
just once or twice a month this will
eventually pay for itself and the
effects are pretty evident too I've been
dealing with a strained muscle in my
back for a few months and every single
time I use this bad boy I definitely
feel loosened up now just like any
product out there there's always going
to be a cheaper alternative and some of
those do in fact feature more speed
options but I can't really speak on the
effectiveness of those other options so
you could definitely go down the budget
friendly route if you wanted to but you
might be taking a bit of a Gamble
I already touched on it a little bit
earlier but I really do love the
companion app it's full of guided
instructions on how to properly use the
massage gun which attachment to use for
a specific body part as well as just the
overall routines in general I think it's
really helpful full of routines for you
to choose from such as warming up before
yoga running working out or even anybody
who plays a sport as well as recovery
routines for those aforementioned
activities as well as lifestyle
activities such as working from home or
traveling and even wellness and ailment
routines for you to choose from plus you
can also just select which body region
that you want to focus on and it will
provide you with a routine there's a
saved tab which is really nice and as
you may assume if there is a specific
routine that you really enjoyed you can
save it and it will always be there for
you to go and select the For You tab is
also a really great tool it's solely
based off the information that you
provided and the activities that you
participate in plus you can always go
back and add more if you want to when
you start a routine you can control the
speed of the theory gun Prime directly
through the app it's also going to
provide you with detailed instructions
on how to properly position the massage
gun which attachment you should be using
where to hold the handle as well as how
much force you should be using for a
specific routine I really like the force
meter now it can be a little bit tricky
to understand exactly how to use it in
the beginning but I still find it really
helpful because you can actually injure
yourself if you're not careful and you
apply too much pressure on an injured
body part it's also really nice that
every single routine is in fact timed
it'll tell you when to switch or when to
just stop completely you might not know
this but you're actually only supposed
to use a massage gun like the theragun
prime for no more than two minutes on
any specific body part
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the theragun prime as you can see
the handle diameters are in fact
different this front one right here is a
little over six inches in diameter while
the back one and the bottom one are
right around four and a half inches in
diameter a little over eight inches tall
and without an attachment it's a little
over seven inches from front to back
made from a hard plastic still feels
really sturdy and durable in my hands
and I feel like I can handle some bumps
and bruises that may happen if you were
to drop it but obviously you want to be
careful with it now I really like the
attachments I like the material they're
made from they're a little bit spongy
like I said earlier I think they're more
versatile than a hard plastic because
you can absolutely use pretty much all
of these on any sensitive areas you know
like your hands like I talked about but
you know they're not too soft at the
same time so you're gonna get a nice
solid massage for any stubborn areas
you're dealing with and in terms of
weight
it's a little over two pounds maybe 2.2
pounds so it's not too heavy and you can
absolutely take it on the road with you
okay so let's talk about the features
with the theragon prime I want to talk
about the attachments first it's really
nice you have four different ones four
specific regions of your body you might
not know exactly what they're meant for
at first so fortunately there is this
little booklet that is included in your
box it's a lot of useful information in
here but most importantly when it comes
to those attachments in the back of this
pamphlet it shows you what each one is
meant for so that's really nice there's
some other good stuff in here too such
as how to properly clean the attachments
and the actual massage gun which all you
have to do is use a disinfectant wipe
which is pretty nice now to turn it on
there's a button in the back you just
hold it for one second it'll come right
on for you and you also have up and down
arrows right here to change your speed
accordingly now you have five LED lights
up here to Signal which speed setting
you're on
and right above the up Arrow there's
three different LED lights that are
going to show you how much battery life
that you have left the battery is
designed to last right around two hours
but that could change depending on what
speed setting you have it on as well as
how much pressure you're applying to
your body now if it were to die for
whatever reason it's bound to die
eventually I would imagine it's only
going to take you around two hours
before it to fully charge
okay so let's do a quick walk around
with the theragun prime I want to
highlight the handle first you do have
multiple different grips for you to
utilize like I said you can use two
hands on here if you want to use it on
somebody's back you know it's really
nice touch Now to turn it on just simply
press this button back here for about a
second
it's gonna kick right in for you to
change the speeds there's two little
arrows right here up and down press up
gonna go all the way up to five you do
have five different LED lights right
here that signal which speed you're
using I'm gonna go ahead and turn this
off because it's kind of loud
right above that up Arrow you do have
three different lights that are going to
correspond with how much battery life
that you have left now let's say your
theragon Prime does die on you well you
can simply plug it in easy access right
there take around two hours or so for it
to fully charge not that bad now you
have four different attachments for you
to use I have the dampener attached at
this moment this is going to be great
for any tender areas especially near any
bones now the thumb right here that's
gonna be great for your lower back as
well as any trigger point therapy you're
wanting to do the standard ball well
this is great for just general usage and
The Cone right here is going to be great
for pinpoint Muscle Therapy now let's
say you want to change the attachments
that's really easy to do just simply
pull out it's going to come right out
for you and you want to make sure that
everything lines up with these two balls
right here and you hear that click it's
not going to come out on your own on its
own really gonna have to pull on it for
it to come out now
in terms of usage and how to properly do
it luckily you do have that companion
app it's going to guide you through
everything it's going to show you
exactly how long you should position the
massage gun on any specific body part
but remember you don't want to go over
two minutes because you definitely run
the risk of injuring yourself and last
but certainly not least you do receive a
nice little travel bag with your
purchase it's going to be really nice
you know you can store everything in
here it's really easy to do I mean
everything fits all your attachments the
massage gun itself and of course your
charger all going to fit nice and snug
in here simply pull on the drawstring
and you can take it on the road with you
foreign
well I personally think that everyone
could benefit from a percussive massage
gun but because of the price for this
one here I think this is going to be
more suited for anyone who's going to
make a point to add this former recovery
into their daily routine if you're
looking for a massage gun to have some
attachments that don't hurt or just
simply feel uncomfortable on your skin I
really think you'll like the ones that
are featured here and the companion app
is just a really great tool in my
opinion it's going to be great for
anyone who does not know how to properly
use a massage gun because every single
routine is in fact guided okay so what
about the people who might not want to
purchase the theragon prime well once
again you know if you don't plan on
incorporating this into your daily
routine just like brushing your teeth
then I wouldn't suggest spending 300 on
massage guns since there are other ones
out there that are much cheaper if
you're looking for your massage gun to
feature a slower speed setting you'll
definitely want to keep looking and some
of you may just prefer going to see a
massage therapist and if that is you
then I highly doubt you're interested in
spending money on a massage gun
[Music]
well friends that's about all I have for
you today on the fairy gun Prime I
really love using this massage gun and
I've added it into my daily routine I
really like how the attachments aren't
too harsh on your body and the companion
app is a great tool for you to use it is
kind of expensive though so I think this
is more tailored for somebody who's
going to use it on a regular basis
thanks for hanging out with me I hope
this video was really helpful and that I
was able to highlight what to expect
with the theragun prime as always stay
on the lookout for my next review but
for now head over to barbin.com and you
can read more about this massage gun
just search barbin theragun prime review
you can find all the details we talked
about here today I'll see y'all next
time
foreign